Register of the Adam Wojciechowski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Adam Wojciechowski papers
1976-2003
2006C60
Wojciechowski, Adam.
5 manuscript boxes (2.0 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Bulletins, underground publications, and printed matter, relating to activities of Solidarnosc and to political conditions in Poland, 1976-2009.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1943 Born in Jaroslaw, Poland
1960-1970 Studies law and history of art at Warsaw University
1974-1976 Coal Equipment Supply Company, Katowice, lawyer
1975- Amnesty International, member
1976 Biuletyn Informacyjny, Komitet Obrony Robotnikow, editorial board
1976-1985 Zwiazek Autorow I Kompozytorow Scenicznych, legal adviser
1977 Ruch Obrony Praw Czlowieka i Obywatela, member
1978 Ruch Wolnych demokratow, member
1978-1978 Opinia, editorial board
1981-1982 Prawda Wolnych Polakow, editor
1995-1999 Promax, legal adviser
1995- Krajowy Fundusz na rzecz Dzieci
Scope and Content of Collection
Bulletins, underground publications, and printed matter, relating to activities of Solidarnosc and to political conditions in Poland.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
NSZZ "Solidarnosc" (Labor organization); Poland Politics and government 1980-1989.
Collection Contents
- Bibliographical file, 1976-2007; 1 (Box 1:)
  Identity cards, passport, printed matter
  - General, 1976-2007 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Police searches, 1979 (Folder 1: 2)
- Correspondence, 2006-2007; 1 (Box 1: 3)
- Subject file, 1977-2009; 1-5 (Box 1-5: 2)
  Bulletins, circulars, clippings, correspondence, documentation of investigation, investigation protocols, flyers, speeches, typescripts arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Akta Dochodzenia Sledztwa (Documentation of Investigation), 1977-1979 (Folder 1:)
    - Volume 1, 1977 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Volume 2, 1978 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Volume 3, 1978 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Volume 4, 1978-1979 (Folder 1: 7)
  - December 1970 Commemoration, 1979 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Elections, 1985 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Komitet Obrony Robotnikow, 1976-1980 (Folder 1:)
    - General, 1976-1980 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Communiqués, 1976 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Lodz Independence Plaque, 1987-2003 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Miedzynarodowa Konferencja Praw Czlowieka, Krakow- Mistrzejowice, 1988 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Niezalezny Ruch Ludowy, 1988-1989 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Ruch Obrony Praw Czlowieka i Obywatela, 1976 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Ruch Wolnych Demokratow, 1978-2009 (Folder 1:)
    - General, 1988-1989 (Folder 1: 16)
    - Program, 1978-2009 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Sprawa Operacyjnego Rozpracowania (Case of Operational Investigation), 1975-1985 (Folder 2:)
    - Volume 1, 1975 (Folder 2: 1)
    - Volume 2, 1975-1976 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Volume 3, 1976-1977 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Volume 4, 1977-1978 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Volume 5, 1978-1979 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Volume 6, 1979 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Volume 7, 1979-1980 (Folder 4: 1)
    - Volume 8, 1981-1982 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Volume 9, 1983-1985 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Volume 10, 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 4)
    - Volume 11, 1974-1975 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Volume 13, 1977 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Underground humor, 1980 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Underground press, 1979-2006 (Folder 5:)
    - Bez Dyktatu, 1979-1982 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Gazeta Ludowa, 1989 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Gospodarz, 1977-1980 (Folder 5: 4)
    - U Progu, 1976-1977 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Zwiazek Mlodych Demokratow, 2006 (Folder 5: 6)
- Printed matter, 1988-2007; 5 (Box 5: 6)
  Various published materials including brochures, pamphlets arranged by title.
  - General, 1990-2007 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Suworow, Wiktor, Akwarium, 1988 (Folder 5: 8)